Kelsey Roberts

in https://www.linkedin.com/pub/kelsey-roberts/71/8a7/185 O https://github.com/kelseyCodes

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Experienced: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, AngularJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Twitter Bootstrap, Git, Github

Proficient: ¡Query, Socket.io, OAuth, Responsive Design, Testing Frameworks (Jasmine, Mocha, Chai)

Basic: MySQL, Sequelize, Ruby, Twitter API, getUserMedia API

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Make It Snappy - http://make-it-snappy.herokuapp.com/

Utilized getUserMedia API and an existing gesture library to incorporate microphone input for an interactive game with motion and sound controls Used CSS animations with a modern, dynamic Angular front-end framework

CodeCast - http://www.codecast.space/

Implemented a dynamic educational tool for teaching programming using the MEANstack, web sockets and audio libraries Created interactive live editor and video lecture functionality that allows users to dynamically interface with code, their classmates and their instructors

EXPERIENCE

Peter Thomas Roth, Assistant to Director of International Sales, New York, New York

Fall 2014 - Winter 2015

Assisted the Director of International Sales in account management of approximately 20 million dollars a year in sales As a temp, covered for the Director of International Sales for over a week independently

PCI Media Impact, External Communications, New York, New York

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

Created, managed and updated website content through WordPress, reorganizing over 50 programs for consistency, clarity and organization Implemented a new social media strategy resulting in an approximate 50% increase in Facebook posts and Tweets

Cammack Health (formerly Cammack LaRhette Consulting), Analyst, New York, New York

Jan 2012 - Jul 2013

Created financial projections for approximately 40 clients, financial and analytical reports and enrollment auditing as part of a two-person team Developed and executed two technical workshops for all employees in Microsoft Excel and Claims Auditing Collected and analyzed all data for a non profit employee benefit survey

EDUCATION

Fullstack Academy Software Engineering Bootcamp with a focus on Fullstack JavaScript

2015

Scripps College 2006-2010

Bachelor of Arts Mathematics, Minor in Anthropology

Thesis: "Exploration of Crystallographic Groups: Symmetry and Wallpaper Groups"

Study Abroad: Morocco; Independent Study Project: Socio-economic Differences between Rural and Urban Morocco through the World of Moroccan **Bread**

Online Education

Ruby, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Node.js, jQuery, Manipulating the DOM

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, results-driven software developer with eclectic experience. Eight months solo travel in developing world, writing and exploring rural cuisine and culture. Strong analytical, communication and interpersonal skills. Extensive volunteer experience; dedicated to creating positive social change through technology.